在本节最后的视频中 我们将介绍放置物体
For this final video in the series, we're gonna cover some placement of objects,
然后介绍如何
and then we're also going to cover maybe
在关卡中放置AI角色
placing an AI character inside the level,
并绘制导航网格作为AI的活动区域
and also dragging out a navmesh to be able to give it interaction.
首先 我们先放置个小木屋
So to begin, what we can do is we can focus on the idea of placing a hut,
因为我想 若我生活在岛上 我会首先建个木屋
because this was what, I guess if I lived on an island, I figured that I would be building a hut.
所以我们到Create Object面板 点进Architecture
So we go to the create objects tab and let's go to architecture,
buildings下面的forest_cabin
buildings and we can go to the forest_cabin.
双击这个 然后移到场景中
Let's double click this and bring this out into our level.
我不太确定门在哪边
Now, I don't know exactly which side the door is on,
显然在这边
obviously this one,
然后我们拖到
and we can pull this back into
树林中去
the actual woods.
现在就是需要删除一些植被的时候
Now this would be one of those cases where you need to cull wherever the vegetation is,
我们关掉材质编辑器 关卡设置面板
so let's go ahead and close material editor, level settings,
回到植物编辑器
when go back to the vegetation editor,
看看哪种灌木是不必要的
and let's find the actual bush.
把它关掉 这样就能快速清除
So maybe we just get rid it of bush, so it's out of the way quickly.
现在我们有了不错的小木屋
So now we have a nice little cabin,
我想再加个小船坞
and I think that we would like a nice little dock,
我不太确定物体在哪个文件夹里
not exactly sure where it is, inside of this,
但我们可以搜索它
so maybe we can type it in, plus we can search.
打开assets/objects/props
We open the assets/objects/props/
maritime/wooden_dock
maritime/wooden_dock,
不错 我们有了船坞
So, that's cool, we have a nice little dock,
我们双击 然后放入场景
and we can click and add,
我们按下2键 转动方向
so let's click the 2 key, we can add that.
需要记住 我们可以复制这个站台
And let's keep in mind one other thing is we can actually duplicate this dock,
我们复制它
we duplicate it
会打开这个面板 先关掉植物编辑器
can open up this, let's change the vegetation editor,
关掉这些
just go ahead and close all these.
我们可以在这里更改站台模型
And now we can change the dock inside of here,
换成我们想要的
maybe it's something else that we would like.
再复制一个并更改 你可以快速的更改模型
Let's go ahead and change one more, you can quickly test things
不然光看名字你都不知道物体长什么样
that otherwise you may not have an idea of what it is.
我想这样就好了 也许
So I like this right here, this dock and maybe
我们可以把这个当作站台末端
we can use this one as the end piece.
另一个看起来太大 所以
This other one looks kind of big, so
开始组建
to start out
我知道这个作为站台末端
I know that this will probably be the end, just because
然后这个作为站台始端
of how it set up, and then this is going to be the beginning.
我们把这两个拼接在一起
If we snap these together,
这里有高度差
leave a height discrepancy,
把这个拉起来
we can pull this up
现在它们是一体了
and now they're all one.
按住Ctrl点击另一个 把这两个都选上
So if I control click and select both of them,
点击Level下的Group
I can go into my Level->Group,
把物体成组 命名为dock
and we're gonna group these objects, we call this dock.
这样做的目的是现在可以同时选择它们
The reason we did this is because now we can select both of them together
以及同时缩放
and they'll scale as they should.
所以这是布置物体的最佳实践
So it's a nice little way of how to set up everything
以实现你想要的效果
to work for you and not against you.
现在我们有了船坞
So now we have the dock right here,
但还缺少一条小路
but maybe it's not exactly set up for a little path.
所以我们回到创建对象面板
So what we can do is go back to our create object,
在Misc中选择Raod
we can go to miscellaneous, let's choose road,
但在这之前 我需要确保地形吸附打开
but before I do that, I want to make sure that I have terrain snapping on.
我把网格吸附关掉 因为没有太大作用
I can turn off the grid snapping as well, this won't matter as much.
我点击Road
So I'm gonna click the road
然后在门前点一下
and I'm click here in front of the door,
点击这 然后在这双击结束
click here and we'll end it there.
打开帮助器
So let's turn on helpers,
可以看见道路在什么位置
so we can see where the road is,
可以看见道路有点扭曲在一起
you notice that they got kind of twisted up,
可能我选错了
that's probably because I didn't have it selected properly.
在这里选择几何吸附
Let's go ahead and do geometry anyways,
选中后 我们重建道路
so with that selected, we can click the forest road,
道路很短
it's going to be very short,
我们把宽度改为2
we can go in and we can change the width to maybe 2,
现在需要选择材质
and what we need to do now is we need to actually select the material.
点击Override Material
So if we click in the override material,
等待它加载
we're gonna wait for it to boot up,
点进materials/roads
we go to the materials/roads,
然后选择
and let's go ahead and do
选road_gravel吧
probably a road... a road_gravel,
现在我们有了沙砾路面
So now we have a gravel road which...
关于道路 有意思的一点是 你可以对齐它们
here's something that is very interesting regarding roads is you can align them,
我若关掉与地面对齐
so if I take off my align to terrain
然后往下拉一点
and I push this down just a little bit,
然后对齐高度图
and align the height map,
便有了与道路下沉的定制高度图
now we have a custom height map that drops with it from the actual door.
现在我们有了屋子 有了道路
So now we've created the house, we've created the path,
船坞也成了组
we have grouped the dock together,
还需要什么呢
what else can be done?
之前说过我们要添加个AI角色
Well, we said that we wanted to add an AI character to this,
所以我们回到Entity
so if I go back to my entities
选择AI 选择一个角色
and I choose AI, we'll choose a character here,
然后确保几何吸附
and we will make sure that we have align to
是开启的
geometry on.
双击左键
By double click,
即可挪到场景中
and we'll hold... bring him into the scene.
我们有了AI角色
So we have our AI character here,
若我点Play
and if we were to click play,
他会掉下来 然后他像在巡逻一样
he would drop down and you would see him kind of walk around,
但实际上并没有走动 因为他还需要张导航网格
it doesn't really walk yet, because he needs a navmesh, but he...
他只会站在那 播放空闲状态动作
he will play some animation, an idle animation, where he's just standing there,
我们可以把他转过来 看看他在干什么
but we can turn around though, so we can see what he's doing.
现在有了AI角色 我们可以把他放在道路上
So now we have our AI character which we can put him on this path, I guess,
现在要做的是 绘制张一有效的导航网格 以引导他活动
and what we need to do now is actually give him a valid navmesh to navigate around him.
要想做到这点 我要先改些东西
So in order to do this, I'm actually going to change something,
点进Display菜单 然后选择隐藏海洋
I'm going to go into the display, and I'm going to choose to hide the ocean.
隐藏后 我可以看见地形的边界
So in hiding the ocean, I can actually see the border or the boundary
在哪里
of where exactly the terrain is,
因为我记得
because as we remember,
关卡地形不是很大 而且导航网格也需要如此
it's not very big and navmash is going to require this,
我们现在要回去
so what we wanna do now is go back,
进入AI 选择Navigation Area
we'll go to AI, we're gonna choose navigation area,
确保几何吸附是
we'll make sure that we have snap to
开启的
geometry on,
我们点击导航区域后 开始绘制区域
we'll click navigation area and we will begin drawing it out, so
由点绘制成区域
it's just going to look for points,
绘制出这片区域 双击结束
and we'll drag it around this area, so we double click.
可以看见引擎在处理导航网格
We'll see that it's processing the navigation mesh,
现在我们把它往上移动
and what we need to do is actually move it upward,
因为导航网格有些低
because right now, the navigation mesh is a little low.
然后再处理一遍 可以看见 在导航区域内的地表都被绘制上网格
So we'll let it process once again and you can see the actual terrain of where the navigation mesh is being drawn.
依然有点低
So we're still a little too low,
我把海洋显示回来
I'm gonna go back to displaying the ocean,
如你所见 这就是不断调整 不断观察效果
and you can see it's just kind of a guess and check game,
最终 会得到我们想要的效果
we're eventually... we're gonna get to the point where
我们不打算把网格绘制到海里
we're not actually drawing the navigation mesh into the ocean,
但我们依然能正确绘制到船坞上
but we still can get it on the dock and surround the areas.
好了 那么
Ok, so...
现在我们在关卡中绘制了导航网格
now we have a navigation mesh that's been drawn out in our level,
我们有了AI 还能到处走动
we have an AI within it and this AI can actually operate wherever he is,
甚至来到船坞 这也是很不错的一点
and he can even come down to the dock and that's what's nice about this,
另外记住 更改物体或地形后
and keep in mind maybe you need to change it
导航网格会自动更新
and the navmesh will update accordingly,
所以它不是那种只生成不更新的
so it's not like it's completely dependent on this and it only generates and then you're stuck with that,
这是你需要记住的关于生成的一点
so it's just something that you need to remember as far as generation.
那么 我想视频就到此结束了
So I think I'm gonna end the video right here,
我们已经放置了船坞
and what we've done is we've laid down a dock, we've
还弄好了道路 放置了建筑
laid down a road for a path, we've stuck the building there,
我们还放置了个AI
we've actually stuck an AI in there,
还生成了导航网格 能让AI到处行动
we've generated a navmesh inside of our island that the AI can operate in.
翻译：他出院了